Meng Vang

Maplewood, MN 55119

(651) 724-5156 ~ meng.vang92@yahoo.com

Portfolio ~ mvang92.github.io/Portfolio/

Software Development Engineer in Test

Experience with front/back-end development along with manual and automation testing. Fast learner, self-driven worker, and a team player with the aptitude to take on new challenges.

Skilled at writing documentation and efficient code using best practices in software engineering.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Java, Kotlin, Python, PHP

Technologies: TestNG, Selenium, React, Express, Angular, Bootstrap, Node, NPM, AJAX, API, JSON

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Cassandra, Amazon RedShift, Firebase

Software: IntelliJ, Eclipse, VS Code, Robo 3T, MySQL Workbench, Microsoft Office Suite

Version Control: GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket

Scrum Tools: Jira, Confluence

Certifications

University of Minnesota – Twin Cities

October 2018

Full-Stack Web Development

Education

University of Wisconsin – River Falls (AACSB)

May 2015

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science and Information Systems

Work Experience

Virgin Pulse

Associate Software Development Engineer in Test (SDET) – Itasca Team

September 2019 – Present

- Collaborate with the development team to write automation tests to test new application features
- Participate in code reviews by suggesting changes to maintain consistency with approved design
- Document bugs by using Jira to create tickets and track progression
- Verify bug fixes through UI and API automation tests and manual testing

Software Engineering Intern – Platform Excellence (PLEX) Team

April 2019 – September 2019

- Worked closely with Scrum and development teams to investigate and resolve client escalated issues
- Wrote automation tests with SDET team using TestNG to prevent errors that may occur for the user
- Contributed to writing and updating documentation in Confluence to keep up with current technology
- Trained a number of newly hired interns and Associate Software Engineers to understand our platform

Freelance Software Developer

CarSpace

October 2018 – Present

- This full-stack application allows car enthusiasts to keep track of their vehicle maintenance history.
- Technologies: MongoDB, Express Server, React, Node, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Firebase

Diet Matador

January 2019 – Present

- This full-stack application promotes healthy eating and provides nutritional facts about common foods.
- Technologies: MongoDB, Express Server, React, Node, JavaScript, Tailwind, Firebase

VangAutoTests

November 2019 – Present

- This repository runs automation tests for new features and bug fix verification tests for my projects.
- Technologies: Java, TestNG, Selenium